earmaster.com 2019-03-29

# Privacy policy

EarMaster ApS cares about the privacy of individuals who visit our website at www.earmaster.com, use our EarMaster App and software, or purchase products in our online store. This Privacy Policy, in compliance with the EU’s GDPR, explains how EarMaster handles the information we obtain from and about our customers, visitors to our Sites, and users of our software. It also tells you about your rights and choices with respect to your personal information, and how you can contact us if you have questions or concerns. Your use of our services and products is subject to this Privacy Policy.

## **1\. How EarMaster Collects Information**

We can obtain personal information relating to you from the sources described below.

Where applicable, we indicate whether and why you must provide us with Personal Information, as well as the consequences of failing to do so. If you do not provide personal information when requested, you may not be able to benefit from our services and products if that information is necessary to provide you with the service or if we are legally required to collect it.

### **i. Personal Information Provided by You**

**Registration, Orders, and Other Information You Provide** **  
**We collect your information, including name, postal address or email address, when you complete an order form, register to use our services, and request that we contact you or provide additional information to you.

**Communications  
** If you contact us directly, such as to request information or access to the services, or for Customer Support, we may receive additional information about you, such as your contact information and the contents of your communication. Besides we may receive additional information when you complete a form on our Sites (see i, ii and iii).

**Payment Information  
** If you pay for access to our services and products, we may collect payment information that you provide, such as bank account information and other information necessary to transfer funds.

### **ii. Information We Collect When You Use the Services**

**Device Information  
** We receive information about your device, including IP address, web browser type, operating system version, mobile device model, device manufacturer and model, language codes, your Internet Service Provider (ISP), unique device identifiers.

**Usage Information  
** We automatically receive information about your interactions with our website, like the pages and other content you view, or the dates and times of your interactions.

**Location Data  
** We may infer your location from the information we collect (for example, your IP address indicates the general geographic region from which you are connecting to the Internet). We may use location information to provide you with features, notifications, marketing, or other content that is influenced by your location, such as showing you the services in your local language or displaying prices in a specific currency or with specific tax rates.

**Cookies and Similar Technologies  
** A cookie is a text-only string of information that a website transfers to the cookie file of the browser on your computer or mobile device. When you use our website, we and our third-party service providers may collect information from you through cookies, web beacons, web server logs, and similar technologies. We may use both session cookies and persistent cookies. By using our services, you consent to the placement of cookies, beacons, and similar technologies in your browser and on emails in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you disable cookies on your browser, some parts of our services may not work fully.

We work with analytics providers such as Google Analytics, which use cookies and similar technologies to collect and analyze information about the use of the Services and report on activities and trends. Google Analytics may also collect information regarding the use of other websites, apps, and online resources. You can learn about Google’s practices by going to [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/), and opt out of them by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, available at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

Our services and products may include links, features or components supplied by third parties, such as the Facebook “Like” button or other interactive tools. Such third-parties may have information practices different than those set forth herein and their use of cookies and similar technologies is not covered by this Privacy Policy. We do not have access to or control over such third parties and encourage you to consult the privacy notices provided by those third parties.

### **iii. Information We Obtain From Third Parties**

We may receive information about you from our third-party partners, such as business or marketing partners. We may combine this information with the other information we collect about you to provide more useful information to you regarding our services. This information may include, for example, your name, address, and billing information.

## **2\. How EarMaster Uses Information**

EarMaster will use information, including Personal Information, for the following purposes:

**Providing Services**  
We use your information to provide, enhance, improve, and personalize our services.

**Facilitating Transactions**  
We use your payment information to facilitate your transactions and payments.

**Analytics**  
We will use your information to understand and analyze how you use our services.

**Marketing**  
We may use your information to contact you about EarMaster’s products and services:

  * via opt-in services such as our Newsletter or similar
  * via automated emails for a limited period of time as part of an interaction with our website, such downloading the free version of EarMaster
  * to send you critical information about the product

**Communications**  
EarMaster will use your information to communicate with you, including to respond to your inquiries and to send emails to an email address you provide to us for customer-service or technical-support purposes.

## **3\. How EarMaster Discloses Information**

**Service Providers**  
We may share your information with our resellers and other third parties that perform services on our behalf after being rightfully appointed to do so.

**As Required by Law and Similar Disclosures**  
We may disclose information about you: (i) if we are required to do so by law, regulation, or legal processes, such as a court order or subpoena; (ii) in response to requests by government agencies, such as law enforcement authorities; (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect against or respond to physical, financial or other harm, injury, or loss of property; or (iv) in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual unlawful activity.

**Consent**  
EarMaster may further disclose your Personal Information with your explicit consent.

## **4\. Data Retention**

We process personal information data in such a way that the highest possible privacy of your personal data is met. Your personal information is kept on our servers and hardware backups in accordance with our security procedures which follow the European Union's legislation for the handling of personal data (GDPR). Your personal data is kept in our system until you have sent us an explicit request to delete them.

## **5\. Our Commitment to Security**

Using authentication and authorization procedures, we ensure as much as possible that unauthorized individuals have no access to your personal data or use services that are exclusive to you.

Unfortunately, transferring data over the Internet cannot be 100% secure. Consequently, despite our best efforts to protect personal data, EarMaster cannot assure or guarantee the security of the information transmitted by the user. Any information you transmit is done at your own risk.

## **6\. Your Rights and Choices**

**Modification or Deletion of Your Personal Information**  
You can update, correct or delete the personal information we save about you (e.g., your email address) by requesting it in writing at [[info@earmaster.com](mailto:info@earmaster.com).](mailto:info@earmaster.com.) To opt-out of receiving our newsletters or marketing emails, you can follow the unsubscribe instructions included in the emails communications you receive or contact us at the above email address.

Please note that we have the right to reject deletion requests that are unduly burdensome or repetitive or that cannot be honored because of legal obligations or ongoing disputes, or where retention is necessary to enforce our agreements or protect our or another party’s rights, property, safety, or security.

**Transcript of Your Personal Information**  
You have the right to obtain a transcript of all your personal information that we have in our files. To do so, please make a written request sent by registered postal mail to EarMaster’s _Data Protection Officer (DPO)_ :

_EarMaster ApS  
Att: Data Protection Officer  
Egaa Havvej 21, 1.  
DK-8250 Egaa  
Denmark _

## **7\. How to Contact Us** _  
_

**General Requests**  
If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or its implementation, you may contact EarMaster by email ([info@earmaster.com](mailto:info@earmaster.com)) or at the following address:

_EarMaster ApS  
Egaa Havvej 21, 1.  
DK-8250 Egaa  
Denmark_

**Contact Our Data Protection Officer**  
EarMaster’s Data Protection Officer (DPO) is the person responsible for supervising the handling of personal information throughout our services and products. Our DPO is Hans Lavdal Jakobsen. He may be contacted by email ([hans@earmaster.com](mailto:hans@earmaster.com)) or at the following address:

_EarMaster ApS  
Att: Data Protection Officer  
Egaa Havvej 21, 1.  
DK-8250 Egaa  
Denmark_

## **8\. Updates to this Privacy Policy**

We will post any adjustments to this Privacy Policy on this page, and the revised versions will be effective when they are posted. Upon updating our privacy policy, we will also change its version number in order to keep track of which terms each user has been agreeing to. We may ask you to review and accept a newer version of our privacy policy in the future if the continued use of our products and services requires it.
